[
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the acronym PEC's?",
        "choices": [
            "Personal entrepreneurial competencies",
            "Personal entrepreneur competition",
            "Professional entrepreneurial competencies",
            "Professional entrepreneurial commodities"
        ],
        "answer": "Personal entrepreneurial competencies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do we mean by an entrepreneur?",
        "choices": [
            "Manages a business for someone else",
            "Accepts the risk of starting and running a business",
            "Owns controlling interest in the stock of a major corporation",
            "Manages a business that operates in more than one country"
        ],
        "answer": "Accepts the risk of starting and running a business"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is an individual who is effective and efficient in communication skills and relates well to people?",
        "choices": [
            "Creative",
            "Profit-oriented",
            "Confident",
            "Possesses people skills"
        ],
        "answer": "Possesses people skills"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call a person who is always looking for an opportunity to have/earn income?",
        "choices": [
            "Confident",
            "Socially-oriented",
            "Profit-oriented",
            "Creative"
        ],
        "answer": "Profit-oriented"
    },
    {
        "question": "When you always stick to the plan, what does it mean?",
        "choices": [
            "Confident",
            "Hardworking",
            "Disciplined",
            "Profit-oriented"
        ],
        "answer": "Disciplined"
    },
    {
        "question": "If he or she works diligently, what kind of a person is he/she?",
        "choices": [
            "Hardworking person",
            "Profit-oriented person",
            "Confident person",
            "Creative person"
        ],
        "answer": "Hardworking person"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what way should the entrepreneur stay in the business to have an edge over the other competitors?",
        "choices": [
            "Provides services",
            "Cater the needs of the customer",
            "Sell all the products",
            "Creative and innovative"
        ],
        "answer": "Creative and innovative"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one refers to good entrepreneurs who render solid dedication to make the business grow?",
        "choices": [
            "Committed",
            "Hardworking",
            "Confident",
            "Creative"
        ],
        "answer": "Committed"
    },
    {
        "question": "When you own a business, you should cope with and thrive on changes. What do you have?",
        "choices": [
            "Disciplined",
            "Sound decision maker",
            "Confident",
            "Ability to accept change"
        ],
        "answer": "Ability to accept change"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the reasons why a self-rating assessment shall be done?",
        "choices": [
            "Use to evaluate an individual PECs",
            "Helps to detect and analyze of the strong and weak points",
            "It serves as a basis to acquire more wealth in the future",
            "Useful in strengthening the entrepreneurial potential"
        ],
        "answer": "Use to evaluate an individual PECs, Helps to detect and analyze of the strong and weak points, It serves as a basis to acquire more wealth in the future, Useful in strengthening the entrepreneurial potential"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one are things that people cannot live without?",
        "choices": [
            "Desires",
            "Needs",
            "Requirements",
            "Wants"
        ],
        "answer": "Needs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What appropriate word or phrase matches the statement 'a process of making a new product to be sold by a business or enterprise to its customers'?",
        "choices": [
            "Entrepreneur",
            "Entrepreneurship",
            "Development",
            "Product development"
        ],
        "answer": "Product development"
    },
    {
        "question": "In selecting the stages in the process of product development, what is the first stage?",
        "choices": [
            "Establish target specifications",
            "Generate product concepts",
            "Identify customer needs",
            "Analyze competitive products"
        ],
        "answer": "Identify customer needs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What details will enable us to contact the client quickly?",
        "choices": [
            "Massage analysis",
            "Personal details",
            "Contra-indication",
            "Other information"
        ],
        "answer": "Personal details"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do people seek wellness massage?",
        "choices": [
            "Wellness massage promotes relaxation.",
            "The public seeks wellness massage to decrease stress.",
            "Wellness massage supports the body's natural restorative mechanisms.",
            "Wellness massage is an enjoyable experience that leaves the body feeling refreshed and revitalized."
        ],
        "answer": "Wellness massage promotes relaxation."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is the best statement that gives the meaning of product development?",
        "choices": [
            "A process of making a new product to be sold by a business or enterprises to its customers",
            "To explore the economic, cultural, and social conditions prevailing in an area",
            "Provides possibilities for a business to expand and make more profits",
            "To refine the product until it becomes ready for production"
        ],
        "answer": "A process of making a new product to be sold by a business or enterprises to its customers"
    },
    {
        "question": "When can you declare that you have a new entrepreneur seize business opportunities?",
        "choices": [
            "After identifying the needs of the community",
            "Finished formulated the entirely new product",
            "Refining the product until it becomes ready for production",
            "Ready to develop a product/or render services"
        ],
        "answer": "After identifying the needs of the community"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following stage in which the needs of the target market are identified, reviewed, and evaluated?",
        "choices": [
            "Concept development",
            "Economic analysis",
            "Project development",
            "Refine specification"
        ],
        "answer": "Concept development"
    },
    {
        "question": "What would you recommend to an aspiring entrepreneur to ensure the products or services he is planning to offer will be patronized and within easy reach of target consumers?",
        "choices": [
            "To follow immediately his business plan",
            "Invests a big amount of money",
            "Hire more workers",
            "Conduct first a SWOT analysis"
        ],
        "answer": "Conduct first a SWOT analysis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ideas justify that you have a unique selling proposition?",
        "choices": [
            "Has a good reason worthy enough to buy your product and not your competitors",
            "Has a substandard quality",
            "Cheaper than the others",
            "Low price with low quality"
        ],
        "answer": "Has a good reason worthy enough to buy your product and not your competitors"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the information gathered during the physical assessment is written?",
        "choices": [
            "Class record",
            "SOAP form",
            "137 form",
            "Record book"
        ],
        "answer": "SOAP form"
    },
    {
        "question": "What can you say about Respiration Rate?",
        "choices": [
            "It is temperature can range from 97.8 °F - 99°F.",
            "It is the number of breaths a person takes per minute.",
            "It is a measurement of the heart beats per minute.",
            "It is the force of the blood pushing against the artery wall."
        ],
        "answer": "It is the number of breaths a person takes per minute."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the value of client consultation in massage?",
        "choices": [
            "It helps you to evaluate any health issue they may have",
            "Just to mingle with the therapist",
            "To acquaint with each other",
            "To meet him/her personally"
        ],
        "answer": "It helps you to evaluate any health issue they may have"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why a client needs to check his vital signs?",
        "choices": [
            "For his comfort and convenience",
            "To detect or monitor his body health status",
            "To have a record of its own",
            "To comply with the required data"
        ],
        "answer": "To detect or monitor his body health status"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is information gathering important when dealing with wellness massage clients?",
        "choices": [
            "To know the client’s favorite spa music",
            "To make the consultation form look longer",
            "To reduce the amount of massage oil used",
            "To identify client needs, preferences, and health conditions for safe and effective treatment."
        ],
        "answer": "To identify client needs, preferences, and health conditions for safe and effective treatment."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the sacred book written by Hindus which describes how shampooing and rubbing were used to reduce fatigue?",
        "choices": [
            "Ayur-Veda",
            "Cong Fau of Tao-Tse",
            "Veda-Ayur",
            "Amma"
        ],
        "answer": "Ayur-Veda"
    },
    {
        "question": "What book title that the ancient Chinese had lists of massage movements with descriptions of their technique?",
        "choices": [
            "Cong Tao of Fau-Tse",
            "Cong Fau of Tao-Tse",
            "Cong Tse of Fau-Tse",
            "Cong Tao of Fau-Tao"
        ],
        "answer": "Cong Fau of Tao-Tse"
    },
    {
        "question": "When was the practice of massage spread and established from the East into Europe?",
        "choices": [
            "3000 BC",
            "1800 BC",
            "500 BC",
            "1450 AD"
        ],
        "answer": "500 BC"
    },
    {
        "question": "What facts or ideas show that the French surgeon Ambroise Pare promoted and developed the use of massage?",
        "choices": [
            "Developed a system of passive and active exercises",
            "Established massage as an effective treatment",
            "Develop massage for use in rehabilitation",
            "He successfully treated Mary Queen of Scots with massage"
        ],
        "answer": "Established massage as an effective treatment"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you assess the value/importance of the evolution of wellness?",
        "choices": [
            "Basis for financial growth",
            "Discoveries were recorded",
            "Enhances the massage therapist’s knowledge and skills",
            "The history guides everyone what is best for the present and in the future"
        ],
        "answer": "Enhances the massage therapist’s knowledge and skills"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Control Cycle, Fire controls Metal. What could this represent in a wellness context?",
        "choices": [
            "Heat reducing stiffness and rigidity",
            "Fire burning all balance",
            "Metal destroying Fire",
            "Fire replacing Earth"
        ],
        "answer": "Heat reducing stiffness and rigidity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "choices": [
            "Earth controls fire",
            "Metal controls wood",
            "Fire controls wood",
            "Wood controls metal"
        ],
        "answer": "Wood controls metal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is NOT connected to a balanced life?",
        "choices": [
            "Feeling beautiful",
            "Feeling lonely",
            "Feeling healthy",
            "Feeling energetic"
        ],
        "answer": "Feeling lonely"
    },
    {
        "question": "In wellness practice, why is harmony of the Three Faculties (body, mind, spirit) considered essential?",
        "choices": [
            "Because it ensures balance of physical health, mental clarity, and inner peace",
            "Because it focuses only on physical appearance",
            "Because it eliminates the need for massage",
            "Because it makes spa treatments faster"
        ],
        "answer": "Because it ensures balance of physical health, mental clarity, and inner peace"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is FALSE in the Health Concepts?",
        "choices": [
            "Lifestyle, diet, and activity level is related to the changes we are seeing in the body.",
            "Massage Therapist are trained to focus on the fact that the body is an integrated organism.",
            "When deciding how to treat a client, therapists must focus on restoring balance to the system.",
            "Gathering as much information about the client so we can see not how the body has changed its function."
        ],
        "answer": "Gathering as much information about the client so we can see not how the body has changed its function."
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of massage can be done with clothing on and the client can seat in any location?",
        "choices": [
            "Chair Massage",
            "Stress reduction",
            "Sports Massage",
            "Medical Massage"
        ],
        "answer": "Chair Massage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call a massage that releases the chronic patterns of tension in the body?",
        "choices": [
            "Swedish massage",
            "Deep tissue",
            "Stone massage",
            "Chair massage"
        ],
        "answer": "Deep tissue"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main idea of medical massage?",
        "choices": [
            "The most common kind of massage, relaxation or stress reduction massage.",
            "Working by prescription, or in a hospital, or in a physical therapist’s office.",
            "The most common kind of massage that is designed to help an athlete prepare for competition",
            "Refers to the type of treatment that might be found in some spa and hair salons."
        ],
        "answer": "Working by prescription, or in a hospital, or in a physical therapist’s office."
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you explain the Acupressure?",
        "choices": [
            "A method of maintaining health, treating disease and alleviating pain by applying pressure or massaging certain points on the body surfaces.",
            "A science of body manipulation where a positive response is affected and brings back the body to normal by using thumb and fingers.",
            "The most widely used form of massage used for relaxation.",
            "The massage releases the chronic patterns of tension in the body."
        ],
        "answer": "A method of maintaining health, treating disease and alleviating pain by applying pressure or massaging certain points on the body surfaces."
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you mean by psychotherapeutic massage?",
        "choices": [
            "Therapists focus on the shifts in awareness and psychological insight",
            "Therapist works with pathologies, pain or recovery from injury.",
            "Therapist works on specific parts of the body that the chiropractor designates.",
            "Therapist working by prescription."
        ],
        "answer": "Therapists focus on the shifts in awareness and psychological insight"
    }
]
